SVEN GLINZ

PROFILE

Current student in Economics with previous experience in Retail Banking, Fixed Income Sales & Trading as well as CCP Risk Management. Strongly interested in finance, capital markets and quantitative subjects such as mathematics and data analytics. Strong communication - as well as quantitative skills demonstrated at university and in various technical and sales-oriented roles at financial companies.

EDUCATION

BsC in Computer Science, ETH Zurich

Sept 2023 - today

BA in Economics, University of St. Gallen (HSG)

Sept 2019 - Jan 2023

Selected Courses: Econometrics, Mathematics for Economists, Capital Markets Law, Money, Banking & Finance,

Data Handling, Financial Derivatives, Investments

Thesis: Margin Procyclicality during Covid 19 - Impact, Drivers and Solutions

Exchange Semester at National Chengchi University, Taiwan (online due to COVID)

One of <10 graduates with a GPA > 5.6 / 6

Maturität, Kantonsschule Frauenfeld

Aug 2012 - Jul 2017

EXPERIENCE

St. Gallen Endowment for Prosperity through Trade

St. Gallen, CH

Junior Data Analyst

Jan 2023 - today

- Rewrote large parts of the internal library and increased reliability and speed by rewriting critical parts in c++
- Generation of plots with ggplot2 for publications and presentations (See eg...)
- Performed all steps of data wrangling, cleaning, mainly with tidyverse packages

Mizuho Securities

Frankfurt, DE / London, UK

Fixed Income Sales & Trading - Summer Intern

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

- Active involvement and Job Shadowing with the credit sales team (Corps, Fins & EM)
- Analyzed a large dataset of historical internal and external trade data to uncover hidden client potential using R
- Was sent to London for a week to Job Shadow the credit Trading Team (Corps, Fins & EM)

Deutsche Börse (EUREX)

Frankfurt, DE
Aug 2021 - Jan 2022

Risk Exposure Management - Intern

- In charge of handling intraday margin calls
- Performing analyses on clients' derivatives portfolios and risk fiures for internal stakeholders and members using SQL
- Insights into the Margin and general Risk Methodology of EUREX

UBS Switzerland AG

St. Gallen, CH

Junior Talent Trainee

Aug 2021 - Jan 2022

· In charge of handling intraday margin calls



github.com/svensglinz

sven.glinz@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/svenglinz

svensglinz.github.io

Skills -

Programming:

RJava CSS, HTML Python SQL

Other:

BloombergMS OfficeGit

Languages

German Native
English Fluent
Spanish Intermediate
French Intermediate
Slovene Beginner